# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello everyone, I am Wang Gang.
# 本期视频我给大家分享一道家常菜
Today I share a home cooking dish with you.
# 爆炒鸭肠
Stir fried duck intestine
# 首先我们准备新鲜鸭肠1000克
First, we prepare fresh duck intestine about 1000 grams
# 然后将鸭肠中的黄油和杂质刮干净备用
Then we clean the duck fat and impurities
# 同学们鸭肠的最终出肉率仅仅为百分之三十五
Because the meat yield of duck intestine is only 35%
# 所以必须将料准备足
We must prepare an adequate amount.
# 黄油刮干净之后开始下一步开始准备清洗
After cleaning the yellow fat, we then prepare to wash it
# 首先我们在盆中加入适量的食用盐（约50克）
First, we add some salt (about 50 grams)
# 加入小苏打1小撮（约2克）
Add a little bit of baking soda (about 2 grams)
# 加入适量的干淀粉（约50克）
Some starch (about 50 grams)
# 加入适量的料酒
Then some cooking wine
# 然后我们用手将鸭肠抓拌5分钟
And then we hand mix the combined ingredients
# 这一步的目的是充分去除鸭肠的黏液
In order to get rid of the slime that the intestine has
# 加小苏打的目的是让鸭肠保持脆度
Baking soda will make the intestine crunchy
# 5分钟之后将鸭肠放入清水中清洗干净备用
After 5 minutes, rinse the intestine well.
# 同学们必须多清洗几遍直到水清为止
We must rinse it a few times until it is clean.
# 清洗干净之后捞出挤干水份备用
Then drain it completely
# 然后将鸭肠每一根拉直摆放整齐
Carefully arrange every intestine straight and nice
# 摆放整齐之后将其切成15厘米左右的小段备用
Then cut them into 15 centimeters sections.
# 鸭肠必须切长一些否则受热收缩之后成菜难看
Cooked duck intestine will shrink, so cut into longer sections now
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next, let’s prepare the supplement ingredients.
# 准备大蒜几颗拍散之后剁碎备用（约20克）
Crush then mince some garlic (about 20 grams)
# 准备红泡椒20克切成小粒备用
Dice fermented red pepper (about 20 grams)
# 准备老姜20克拍散之后剁碎备用
Crush and mince some ginger (about 20 grams)
# 准备几个小米辣和二荆条切碎备用
Dice a few "Xiaomila" and "Erjingtiao" chili peppers
# 不能吃辣的同学可以不加
If you don’t eat hot and spicy, you can skip this.
# 准备仔姜1小块切成丝备用
Cut a small nugget of baby ginger long and thin strips (julienne)
# 准备芹菜几根切成小段备用
Cut a few Chinese celeries into sections.
# 最后准备小葱头几根切成小段备用
And last, cut some green onion white into small sections.
# 下一步开始提前调味
Next, we will season the supplement ingredients before cooking.
# 首先我们在辅料碗中加入食用盐1克
First, we add 1 gram of salt into the bowl of supplement ingredients
# 加入胡椒粉1小勺（约0.5克）
1 teaspoon of white pepper powder (about 0.5 gram)
# 加入少许白糖提鲜
Add a small amount of sugar
# 加入生抽酱油5克
Light soy sauce 5 grams
# 加入少许陈醋（约1克）
Dark vinegar 1 gram
# 下一步开始制作
Now we are ready to cook
# 首先我们在锅中加入适量的清水开大火烧开
First, we boil some water with high heat
# 中途加入适量的料酒
During this time, add some cooking wine
# 大火烧开之后将处理好的鸭肠下锅焯水10秒钟
When the water is boiling, add the duck intestine and parboil for 10 seconds
# 这一步的目的是将鸭肠烫卷（约6成熟）
This is to cook it up to 60%, and it will curl
# 下一步我们开始制作
Then we will do the stir-frying
# 首先我们把锅烧热
Heat the wok first
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的油滑锅
Then add some oil to coat the wok
# 滑好锅之后将热油倒出
After the coating, pour out the heated oil
# 再加入适量的底油
Then add some base oil
# 油温6成热之后加入姜蒜粒和泡椒爆香
When the oil reaches about 180°C, add ginger, garlic, and fermented pepper and fry to get the aroma
# 中途再加入豆瓣酱4克炒香炒出红油
Add 4 grams of doubanjiang (aka broad bean paste) and stir fry it till you see the red oil
# 豆瓣酱炒香之后将焯好水的鸭肠下锅翻炒几下
When you smell the doubanjiang aroma, add the duck intestine and stir fry
# 翻炒均匀之后开始调味
When the intestine is evenly coated with current ingredients, we’ll start to add spice and seasonings
# 锅中加入适量的白糖和胡椒粉调味
Add some sugar and white pepper powder
# 加入料酒5克从锅边淋入
Add cooking wine 5 grams from the side of the wok
# 最后加入老抽1克调底色
Add dark soy sauce 1 gram to add color
# 然后开中火翻炒几下
Turn the burner to mid-heat and stir fry a bit more
# 翻炒均匀之后再加入准备好的辅料（辣椒，仔姜丝，芹菜）.
When it is evenly tossed, add the supplement ingredients. (pepper, young ginger, Chinese celery)
# 开中火翻炒至断生之后再加入适量的水淀粉勾成薄芡
With mid-heat, half cook the supplement ingredients then add a little slurry
# 最后加入少许明油翻炒均匀即可出锅装盘
Last, add a little cold oil and fry it evenly, then serve.
# 一道非常美味的爆炒鸭肠就制作完成
We now get a very tasty stir fried duck intestine.
# 下面开始技术总结
Next, technical summary.
# 第一， 最好选择新鲜鸭肠，冰冻鸭肠口感略低
# First, fresh duck intestine is the best. Frozen ones have a less good texture.
# 第二， 鸭肠必须加盐淀粉料酒多抓洗几遍，否则会有腥味
# Second, duck intestine must be thoroughly cleaned with salt, starch, and cooking wine, and to hand mix, in order to get rid of the unpleasant smell.
# 第三， 辅料下锅之前先调味可以减少翻炒的时间
# Third, in order to shorten the stir fry time, it is better to season the supplement ingredients first.
# 第四， 最后可以勾薄芡也可以不勾芡
# Fourth, you can skip adding the slurry in the last step if you prefer so.
# 爆炒鸭肠的技术总结完毕
# That completes the technical summary for stir fried duck intestine.